Arthur S. Moody Papers
Arthur S. Moody Papers
1903-1961
Moody, Arthur S.
9 [?] linear ft.
Papers of the Methodist Episcopal clergyman; correspondence and church reports
2639548
Biographical History
Arthur S. Moody was an American Methodist Episcopal clergyman. He attended Syracuse University, graduating in 1909, and served at Methodist Episcopal churches in several New York State towns and villages.
1903-1909 Student, Syracuse University
1909-1911 Pastor, Methodist Episcopal Church, Parish, New York
1911-1916 Pastor, Methodist Episcopal Church, West Winfield, New York
1916-1919 Pastor, Methodist Episcopal Church, Mohawk, New York
1919 Assistant Superintendent of Adult Work, Methodist Episcopal Church Board of Education, St. Louis, Missouri
1920 Assistant Superintendent of Adult Work, Methodist Episcopal Church Board of Education, New York
1921-1923 Pastor, Methodist Episcopal Church, Lowville, New York
1925-1927 Pastor, Erwin Methodist Episcopal Church, Syracuse, New York
1927-1933 D.S., Geneva (New York) District
1933-1936 Pastor, Centenary Methodist Episcopal Church, Syracuse, New York
1936-1944 Pastor, Methodist Episcopal Church, Homer, New York
1944-1946 Pastor, Methodist Episcopal Churches, Trumansburg and Jacksonville, New York
1946-1954 Pastor, Methodist Episcopal Church, Jacksonville, New York
1954-1959 Pastor, McLean United Church [location?]
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Arthur S. Moody Papers consist primarily of correspondence, and relate entirely to Moody's pastorships and other activities with the Methodist Episcopal Church. New York churches represented include those of Plainville, West Winfield, Homer, Lowville, Syracuse, and Geneva; there is also some correspondence with Syracuse University from Moody's student days. The Geneva district correspondence includes church reports covering the years 1927-1933, and there are also copies of Moody's "Country Parson" column written for American Agriculturalist.
Arrangement of the Collection
Material is arranged chronologically but sorted by organization, so there is some overlap of time period in the various topics (for example, Syracuse University covers 1903-1909 while the next subject, Plainville Parish, covers 1905-1906).
Subject and Genre Headings
Church and clergy; New York State; Moody, Arthur S.; Methodist Episcopal Church. Board of Education.; Church records and registers -- New York (State); Methodist Episcopal Church -- Clergy.; Methodist Episcopal Church -- New York (State); Methodists -- New York (State); Correspondence.; Annual reports.; Pastors.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Syracuse University, 1903-1909 (Box 1)
  - Plainville Parish, 1905-1906 (Box 1)
  - Paris, New York, 1909-1911 (Box 1)
  - West Winfield, New York, 1911-1916 (Box 1)
  - Mohawk, 1916-1919 (Box 2)
  - Methodist Episcopal Church Board of Education, St. Louis, 1919 (Box 3)
  - Methodist Episcopal Church Board of Education, New York, 1920 (Box 3)
  - Lowville Methodist Episcopal Church
    - 1921-1923 (Box 3)
    - 1923-1925 (Box 3)
  - Erwin Methodist Episcopal Church, 1925-1927 (Box 5)
  - Geneva District
    - 1928-1929 (Box 5)
    - 1929 (Box 6)
    - 1930 (Box 7)
    - 1931-1932 (Box 8)
    - 1932-1933 (Box 9)
  - Geneva District, individual churches annual reports, 1927-1933
    - Aloquin to Fint (Box 10)
    - Geneva to Middlesex (Box 11)
    - Newark to Sheldrake (Box 12)
    - Sodus to Wolcott (Box 13)
  - Syracuse Centenary Methodist Episcopal Church, 1933-1936 (Box 14)
  - Homer Methodist Episcopal Church, 1936-1944 (Box 14)
  - Jacksonville Methodist Episcopal Church, 1944-1947 (Box 14)
  - "Country Parson" in American Agriculturalist, 1959-1961 (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 14)